<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ramblings on sheldonhull.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/ramblings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ramblings on sheldonhull.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedupe Google Drive with RClone</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-19-dedupe-google-drive-with-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-19-dedupe-google-drive-with-rclone/</guid>
      <description>An issue with duplicates I migrated from Amazon Cloud Drive to a paid Google Drive account. To facilate this move, I used a paid service called MultCloud. For me, Comcast prevents unlimited data, so it would have been challenging to manage 1.5TB of video and photography files movement by downloading then reuploading to Google Drive.
I ran into issues due to hitting rate limiting with Multcloud. As a result, I had to work through their awkard user interface to relaunch those jobs, which still had failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time With Family - Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-12-31-time-with-family-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-12-31-time-with-family-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my personal quest as a creative who has a passion for videography to try and capture simple moments during my life with family. There are plenty of epic indie films, and I can&amp;rsquo;t commit this type of time with a day job, family, and other interests. I think this is a good start. Thanks to Robert &amp;amp; Steph for their hospitality and making this a special thanksgiving. Was a wonderful time with family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight in the Little Moments</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-11-10-delight-in-the-little-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-11-10-delight-in-the-little-moments/</guid>
      <description>This last Easter I had some fun with the kids at their grandparents. Remember the days of spinning until you were nauseous? Was fun to watch the kids enjoying this so I took a few clips, nothing fancy, just a snapshot of enjoying the little moments in life.
Thinking I&amp;rsquo;ll try this approach for a while. Small 2 minute videos that aren&amp;rsquo;t refined a lot are easy for me to produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World Little Ella</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-08-welcome-to-the-world-little-ella/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-08-welcome-to-the-world-little-ella/</guid>
      <description>Proud to announce Ella the newest addition to my family joined us today @ 6:19pm, weighing in at 6lbs and 11 ounces. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s 6lbs of cuteness. :-) I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly blessed to have this third addition to my family, and look forward to treasuring every moment with her. God sure knows how to give an amazing gift!
It was a rough 24 hours resulting in our first cesarean experience. This was a bit intense, but Sarah pulled through as a trooper, and we are now finished with post-operation recovery, and enjoying time with our new bundle of awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery is a Marathon, Not a Sprint - Hurricane Harvey</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-03-recovery-is-a-marathon-not-a-sprint-hurricane-harvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-03-recovery-is-a-marathon-not-a-sprint-hurricane-harvey/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that the road to recovery is not an instant process. Right now we have a ton of volunteers and people working to help those in need. I&amp;rsquo;m reminding myself, as much as any readers here, the process to recovery for people most impacted is not a single week of effort event. In some cases, entire homes were lost and without flood insurance, the financial devastation can be profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Not-So Waterlogged Texan - Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-not-so-waterlogged-texan-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-not-so-waterlogged-texan-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>info &amp;ldquo;Updated: 2017-08 1:30pm Wednesday&amp;rdquo; Better than expected, we are looking to be back in our house Thursday. Apparently some SUV&amp;rsquo;s are just starting to gain access. Don&amp;rsquo;t want to risk it so giving it a little extra time. That&amp;rsquo;s much better than I expected at beginning of this whole situation! Relief efforts mentioned at bottom are underway at nwvineyard.com so if you are looking to help the Tomball/Northwest Houston area that&amp;rsquo;s one place to help or find out how to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Waterlogged Texan Reporting In from Northpoint Tomball</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-waterlogged-texan-reporting-in-from-northpoint-tomball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-waterlogged-texan-reporting-in-from-northpoint-tomball/</guid>
      <description>Waterlogged What a crazy weekend. Choose to evacuate the family as water was slowly creeping up closer to the house. I was ready today when I made it back to the house to see the water in the house, but to my astonishment it was only half-way up the driveway. Turning down the road 1 house away, many houses did not fare so well, and water looks to have made it in many homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrawide Monitor - Samsung CF971 - First impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-16-ultrawide-monitor-samsung-cf971-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-16-ultrawide-monitor-samsung-cf971-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of multiple monitors for a long time. I moved to a triple screen setup years ago, and up until recently, had no desire to try anything different.
Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the replacement. The holy grail of productivity, immersion, as well as usability. Ultrawides :-)
Don&amp;rsquo;t you miss the extra screen? No. The width of the screen is plenty for 2 full Visual Studio environments, or 3 text editors side by side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing VirtualBox Only Showing 32bit Windows OS Options</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-11-fixing-virtual-box-only-showing-32bit-windows-os-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-11-fixing-virtual-box-only-showing-32bit-windows-os-options/</guid>
      <description>Original help was identified from this article Why is VirtualBox only showing 32 bit guest versions on my 64 bit host OS?
In browsing through the comments, I saw mention that the root issue is that Hypervisor running interferes with Virtualboxes virtual management, so I disabled Hypervisor service, repaired the install, and rebooted. I also disabled automatic start for Hypervisor. This resolved the issue without requiring the uninstallation of the Hypervisor feature in Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify vs Google Play</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-05-spotify-vs-google-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-05-spotify-vs-google-play/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently switched over to Spotify for the nth time to explore the Spotiverse world and compare as a long time Google Play Music user. This is a big deal for me, as I was a first adopter of Google Play and have used it before All Access, and subscribed immediately to All Access once it was released. As a ravenous music consumer, I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred the subscription model for instant, on demand access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Hack: When you need a mouse pad</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-02-24-life-hack-when-you-need-a-mouse-pad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-02-24-life-hack-when-you-need-a-mouse-pad/</guid>
      <description>My Logitech Master mouse went on the fritz&amp;hellip; Requiring me to use my trusty Microsoft mouse. This is an optical based mouse based mouse that started driving me insane with the lack of precision. This exhibited random skips and overall lack of agreeability. I ran across some posts mentioning optical mice have issues with certain surfaces making it hard to detect precise movements and suggested using a surface with a pattern or irregularity, even a piece of paper being scribbled on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ManicTime - Timetracking Automation Done Right</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-09-manictime-timetracking-automation-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-09-manictime-timetracking-automation-done-right/</guid>
      <description>Tracking time is always a beast. With the amount of context switching many developers do, it can be tough to remember how much time went to each project. With companies looking to track effort on sprints, hours on a client project, or (as in my case) just a dev wanting to better evaluate the productive use of time, this app fills some gaps that others don&amp;rsquo;t.For instance, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried tools such as Toggl, and similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Traditional Birthday Song Is Terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>The traditional birthday song is terrible.It&amp;rsquo;s never really changed. It&amp;rsquo;s like singing a dirge. It&amp;rsquo;s really really hard for people to sing anywhere close to on key. We all sing it because we have to, but there is this feeling of regret, like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it for you, but just because I love you&amp;rdquo;. It is followed by &amp;ldquo;Many mourns&amp;rdquo; by the closest available family clown. Apparently, the roots were back in the 19th century, and wikipedia says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizzicato Pizza</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-29-pizzicato-pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-29-pizzicato-pizza/</guid>
      <description>Had a blast making this song. Unfortunately, creating video of slow motion pizza cutting was going to be a bit awkward to do, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like asking a pizza place to let me stand behind the counter and video pizza assembly. :-)Best listened to with headphones, not a phone speaker :-)  This was an experimentation with several new tools for me.
song creation I first used Presonus Studio One 3 to record some basic track parts like the guitar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Internet With Less Ads - Adguard</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-20-an-internet-with-less-ads-adguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-20-an-internet-with-less-ads-adguard/</guid>
      <description>Ads&amp;hellip;I know they employ people, make the world go round, gave us google&amp;hellip;. but seriously I hate almost all ads. If my ranking in google search drops to the end because of this post&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip;. I&amp;rsquo;m ok with that.
Adguard I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this for over a year as a beta tester (they provided license for me to test and use latest versions). I had a perfect case to demo the craziness of some sites with ads vs using Adguard the other day and figured I&amp;rsquo;d share it if you&amp;hellip; like me&amp;hellip; hate the clutter they provide on many sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAW Dive 02 - BFD3 - Drumming for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-11-daw-dive-02-bfd3-drumming-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-11-daw-dive-02-bfd3-drumming-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>Creating tracks at home can be very intensive in time, so I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a better way to bring a larger sound to a track with less effort. One of the big gaps for me has been the drum parts. I&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated a few options, and finally dived into BFD3 for this latest project that is a post-rock style track. This was my first time diving into BFD3 for a full song, so I had a bit to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncovery &amp; Arq - Syncing &amp; Backup</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-09-syncovery-arq-syncing-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-09-syncovery-arq-syncing-backup/</guid>
      <description>Syncovery &amp;amp; Arq 5I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of file sync/backup utilities. The primary definition to get right is that there are two main functions people try to achieve with this type of software.
 File Syncing: Syncing Files Between Cloud and Local File Backup: Preserving Files, sometimes with versioning, in order to protect against loss. These two approaches require a diffferent solution many times, as focusing on file syncing means you are more at risk, as handing conflicting sync scenarios might cause loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAW Dive 1 - Getting Started - Studio One 3</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-20-daw-dive-1-getting-started-studio-one-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-20-daw-dive-1-getting-started-studio-one-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a geek, software nerd, and a musician. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been stagnating lately in my musical progression I decided to dive into trying to produce some recordings of some of my music, hoping to spice up the old brain.I have a lot to learn. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty humbling, but despite being a musician and a developer with some decent tinkering ability, I&amp;rsquo;ve found getting into recording and production a bit challenging on certain things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ableton Live &amp; Lemur Setup (From a Windows User)</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-17-ableton-live-lemur-setup-from-a-windows-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-17-ableton-live-lemur-setup-from-a-windows-user/</guid>
      <description>Had a chance to look at this program thanks to the generosity of the developer. They had a promotion that ended prematurely and they sent me a license as a goodwill gesture. Pretty fantastic service, and thanks to them for this.The documentation was a little sparse for the Windows setup, so I ran into some complications getting it to work.
I have used TouchOSC, and had some difficulty with configuring it for windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack for Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-14-lack-for-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-14-lack-for-nothing/</guid>
      <description>The message of this song is one that that has been driving itself home as more and more important to me. We are not viewed in our frailty as we come before God to worship Him. We are not judged and condemned. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t look and tell us to come back when we are in a better place. Instead, just as the author of Hebrews writes (Heb 10), we can come with bold confidence, knowing that the way has been made for us in Christ, with us being viewed through the &amp;ldquo;curtain&amp;rdquo; of Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Desktop Workflow Improvements</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-29-remote-desktop-workflow-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-29-remote-desktop-workflow-improvements/</guid>
      <description>Remote server management is a fact of life for folks involved with sql server. Since we work so often with remote machines I looked into a few tools that provided a better workflow than the default Microsoft tools. This one came out as the winner by far.
A better remote desktop manager First off, if you are using RDC&amp;hellip;. why? At least move up to RDCMan, a microsoft tool that allows for much quick context switching between machines, inherited password settings for a group of servers, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Search Only Results from the last year</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-04-27-google-search-only-results-from-the-last-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-04-27-google-search-only-results-from-the-last-year/</guid>
      <description>Tech changes quick. Reading google postings from something in 2009 is not my first choice.I found an option after digging through some google discussion posts on how to setup the default search in chrome (also applies to other browsers) to automatically apply the advanced filter option for &amp;ldquo;results in last year&amp;rdquo;.
 Go to chrome settings menu  Navigate to manage search engines  Enter the new search engine option .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFS Work-Item Fancy Filtering</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-03-18-tfs-work-item-fancy-filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-03-18-tfs-work-item-fancy-filtering/</guid>
      <description>If you want to create a TFS query that would identify work items that have changed, but were not changed by the person working it, there is a nifty way to do this.The filtering field can be set to &amp;lt;&amp;gt; another field that is available, but the syntax/setup in Visual Studio is not intuitive. It&amp;rsquo;s in the dropdown list, but I&amp;rsquo;d never noticed it before!
AND &amp;#39; Changed By &amp;#39; &amp;lt;&amp;gt; [Field] &amp;#39; Assigned to Note that you don&amp;rsquo;t include brackets on the assigned to field, and that the &amp;lt;&amp;gt; [Field] is not a placeholder for you to type the field name in, it&amp;rsquo;s actually the literal command for it to parse this correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeker &amp; Servant: Fantastic Music with incredible dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-01-20-seeker-servant-fantastic-music-with-incredible-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-01-20-seeker-servant-fantastic-music-with-incredible-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Just recently discovered this artist after being exposed to an article from Worship Leader magazine. Fantastic dynamics. The dynamics and beautiful harmonies are pretty darn close to what I&amp;rsquo;d love experimenting with if I had a group of folks playing those instruments. Interestingly, the vocal harmonies are very simple, but I found very beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s compromised of a tenor and a baritone range, and is a fresh change stuff like Shane and Shane which both have incredibly high ranges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Tools: XYplorer (review #1) - Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/dev-tools-x-yplorer-review-1-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/dev-tools-x-yplorer-review-1-catalog/</guid>
      <description>currently on version 14.60 I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of finding tools that help automate and streamline things that should are routine actions.Surprisingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve found it incredibly challenging to move away from the default Windows Explorer for file management, as the familiarity it offers makes it somewhat tough to be patient with learning an alternative, especially if the alternative offers more complication. That&amp;rsquo;s where I stood with XYPlorer for sometime. It is a developer&amp;rsquo;s tool first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>