<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on sheldonhull.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on sheldonhull.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify vs Google Play</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-05-spotify-vs-google-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-05-spotify-vs-google-play/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently switched over to Spotify for the nth time to explore the Spotiverse world and compare as a long time Google Play Music user. This is a big deal for me, as I was a first adopter of Google Play and have used it before All Access, and subscribed immediately to All Access once it was released. As a ravenous music consumer, I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred the subscription model for instant, on demand access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Traditional Birthday Song Is Terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>The traditional birthday song is terrible.It&amp;rsquo;s never really changed. It&amp;rsquo;s like singing a dirge. It&amp;rsquo;s really really hard for people to sing anywhere close to on key. We all sing it because we have to, but there is this feeling of regret, like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it for you, but just because I love you&amp;rdquo;. It is followed by &amp;ldquo;Many mourns&amp;rdquo; by the closest available family clown. Apparently, the roots were back in the 19th century, and wikipedia says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Traditional Birthday Song Is Terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-03-the-traditional-birthday-song-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>The traditional birthday song is terrible.It&amp;rsquo;s never really changed. It&amp;rsquo;s like singing a dirge. It&amp;rsquo;s really really hard for people to sing anywhere close to on key. We all sing it because we have to, but there is this feeling of regret, like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it for you, but just because I love you&amp;rdquo;. It is followed by &amp;ldquo;Many mourns&amp;rdquo; by the closest available family clown. Apparently, the roots were back in the 19th century, and wikipedia says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizzicato Pizza</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-29-pizzicato-pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-29-pizzicato-pizza/</guid>
      <description>Had a blast making this song. Unfortunately, creating video of slow motion pizza cutting was going to be a bit awkward to do, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like asking a pizza place to let me stand behind the counter and video pizza assembly. :-)Best listened to with headphones, not a phone speaker :-)  This was an experimentation with several new tools for me.
song creation I first used Presonus Studio One 3 to record some basic track parts like the guitar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAW Dive 02 - BFD3 - Drumming for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-11-daw-dive-02-bfd3-drumming-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-11-daw-dive-02-bfd3-drumming-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>Creating tracks at home can be very intensive in time, so I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a better way to bring a larger sound to a track with less effort. One of the big gaps for me has been the drum parts. I&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated a few options, and finally dived into BFD3 for this latest project that is a post-rock style track. This was my first time diving into BFD3 for a full song, so I had a bit to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAW Dive 1 - Getting Started - Studio One 3</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-20-daw-dive-1-getting-started-studio-one-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-20-daw-dive-1-getting-started-studio-one-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a geek, software nerd, and a musician. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been stagnating lately in my musical progression I decided to dive into trying to produce some recordings of some of my music, hoping to spice up the old brain.I have a lot to learn. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty humbling, but despite being a musician and a developer with some decent tinkering ability, I&amp;rsquo;ve found getting into recording and production a bit challenging on certain things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ableton Live &amp; Lemur Setup (From a Windows User)</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-17-ableton-live-lemur-setup-from-a-windows-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-17-ableton-live-lemur-setup-from-a-windows-user/</guid>
      <description>Had a chance to look at this program thanks to the generosity of the developer. They had a promotion that ended prematurely and they sent me a license as a goodwill gesture. Pretty fantastic service, and thanks to them for this.The documentation was a little sparse for the Windows setup, so I ran into some complications getting it to work.
I have used TouchOSC, and had some difficulty with configuring it for windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack for Nothing</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-14-lack-for-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-09-14-lack-for-nothing/</guid>
      <description>The message of this song is one that that has been driving itself home as more and more important to me. We are not viewed in our frailty as we come before God to worship Him. We are not judged and condemned. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t look and tell us to come back when we are in a better place. Instead, just as the author of Hebrews writes (Heb 10), we can come with bold confidence, knowing that the way has been made for us in Christ, with us being viewed through the &amp;ldquo;curtain&amp;rdquo; of Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeker &amp; Servant: Fantastic Music with incredible dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-01-20-seeker-servant-fantastic-music-with-incredible-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-01-20-seeker-servant-fantastic-music-with-incredible-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Just recently discovered this artist after being exposed to an article from Worship Leader magazine. Fantastic dynamics. The dynamics and beautiful harmonies are pretty darn close to what I&amp;rsquo;d love experimenting with if I had a group of folks playing those instruments. Interestingly, the vocal harmonies are very simple, but I found very beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s compromised of a tenor and a baritone range, and is a fresh change stuff like Shane and Shane which both have incredibly high ranges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>