<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on sheldonhull.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on sheldonhull.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 23:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating From Hipchat To Slack</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2019-02-07-migrating-from-hipchat-to-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2019-02-07-migrating-from-hipchat-to-slack/</guid>
      <description>Last Minute Migration? If you are about to perform a last minute migration here&amp;rsquo;s a couple tips as you jump ship from Hipchat and move to Slack. Hipchat is sunsetting I believe on Feb 15th, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d share what I do have in case it&amp;rsquo;s helpful, as it won&amp;rsquo;t stay tremendously relevant for long.
Problem: Hipchat access will be removed and you need more time Export the hipchat content to a file and upload to your own s3 bucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server Database Experimentation Assistant - How to Run a Capture</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2019-02-07-sql-server-database-experimentation-assistance-how-to-run-a-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2019-02-07-sql-server-database-experimentation-assistance-how-to-run-a-capture/</guid>
      <description>DEA Very basic look at the setup as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find much documentation on this when I last tried this out in 2018. Maybe it will help you get started a little more quickly. I&amp;rsquo;ve not had a chance to leverage the actual comparisons across a large workload. When I originally wrote up the basics on this last year I found my needs required more customized load testing approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedupe Google Drive with RClone</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-19-dedupe-google-drive-with-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-19-dedupe-google-drive-with-rclone/</guid>
      <description>An issue with duplicates I migrated from Amazon Cloud Drive to a paid Google Drive account. To facilate this move, I used a paid service called MultCloud. For me, Comcast prevents unlimited data, so it would have been challenging to manage 1.5TB of video and photography files movement by downloading then reuploading to Google Drive.
I ran into issues due to hitting rate limiting with Multcloud. As a result, I had to work through their awkard user interface to relaunch those jobs, which still had failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTFS Compression and SQL Server Do Not Play Well Together</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-08-ntfs-compression-and-sql-server-dont-play-well-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-08-08-ntfs-compression-and-sql-server-dont-play-well-together/</guid>
      <description>Wanted to be proactive and move a database that was in the default path on C:\ to a secondary drive as it was growing pretty heavily.
What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize was the adventure that would ensure.
Lesson 1 Don&amp;rsquo;t move a SQL Server database to a volume that someone has set NTFS Compression on at the drive level.
Lesson 2 Copy the database next time, instead of moving. Would have eased my anxious dba mind since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting a Directory That Has a Trailing Space Shouldn&#39;t Be This Hard</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-07-23-deleting-a-directory-that-has-a-trailing-space-shouldn-t-be-this-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-07-23-deleting-a-directory-that-has-a-trailing-space-shouldn-t-be-this-hard/</guid>
      <description>It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this hard. This is a consumate #windowsmoment
If you occasionally use something like Robocopy, or other command line tool, it can be possible to create a directory with a trailing slash. For instance
robocopy &amp;#34;C:\test\Taco&amp;#34; &amp;#34;C:\Burritos\are\delicious &amp;#34; This trailing space would be actually used by Robocopy to initialize a directory that has a trailing space in the name. This can appear as a duplicator in explorer, until you try to rename and notice a trailing slash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL .NET Requirements</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-30-offline-net35-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-30-offline-net35-install/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server Install Requirements SQL Server Installation requirements indicate .NET 3.5, 4.0, or 4.6 depending on the version. This is not including SSMS. At this point you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use SSMS from any SQL ISO. Just install SQL Management Studio directly. See for more details on this - Improvements with SSMS 2016 - Update SSMS With PS1
From a quick review here&amp;rsquo;s what you have regarding .NET requirements for the database engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Cracking</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-29-git-cracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-29-git-cracking/</guid>
      <description>info &amp;ldquo;Resources&amp;rdquo; - GitKraken - Source Tree - Posh-Git - Cmder
 Git Some Pain Having come from a Team Foundation Server background, I found Git to be a bit confusing. The problem is primarily the big difference in a distributed version control system vs non-distributed. In addition to that complexity the terminology is not exactly intuitive. A lot of phrases like PULL have different results depending on what step you are in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration To Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-18-migration-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2018-03-18-migration-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the process of migrating my site to it&amp;rsquo;s final home (as far as my inner geek can be satisfied staying with one platform)&amp;hellip; Jekyll.
Jekyll Jekyll is a static website generator that takes plain markdown files and runs through through files that are basically templates for the end html content, allowing flexibility in content generation. The result ends up being a static website with beautifully generated typography, search, pagination, and other great features for a blogging engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrawide Monitor - Samsung CF971 - First impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-16-ultrawide-monitor-samsung-cf971-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-16-ultrawide-monitor-samsung-cf971-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>As a developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of multiple monitors for a long time. I moved to a triple screen setup years ago, and up until recently, had no desire to try anything different.
Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the replacement. The holy grail of productivity, immersion, as well as usability. Ultrawides :-)
Don&amp;rsquo;t you miss the extra screen? No. The width of the screen is plenty for 2 full Visual Studio environments, or 3 text editors side by side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing VirtualBox Only Showing 32bit Windows OS Options</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-11-fixing-virtual-box-only-showing-32bit-windows-os-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-11-fixing-virtual-box-only-showing-32bit-windows-os-options/</guid>
      <description>Original help was identified from this article Why is VirtualBox only showing 32 bit guest versions on my 64 bit host OS?
In browsing through the comments, I saw mention that the root issue is that Hypervisor running interferes with Virtualboxes virtual management, so I disabled Hypervisor service, repaired the install, and rebooted. I also disabled automatic start for Hypervisor. This resolved the issue without requiring the uninstallation of the Hypervisor feature in Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring SQL Server With Powershell And SMO Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-09-exploring-sql-server-with-powershell-and-smo-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-09-exploring-sql-server-with-powershell-and-smo-basics/</guid>
      <description>SqlServer Powershell Cmdlets 2017 - Initialize Look Diving into the Sql Server Management Objects library can be a pretty interesting process. You get to work with database objects as in a new way, and begin manipulating and execute code in a much different approach than purely using T-SQL. Powershell offers a unique way to interact with prebuilt cmdlets, and you can explore leveraging .NET in powershell as well to have a powerful toolkit of options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataedo - First Look</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-07-dataedo-first-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-07-dataedo-first-look/</guid>
      <description>info &amp;ldquo;update 2019-02-22&amp;rdquo; Image links broken. Since their product is continually improving, I&amp;rsquo;m going to just link to their product here instead so you can review their latest demo content there. Dataedo. Overall, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the product and think it has been improved over time. There are SQL scripts for bulk updating certain values on their website that can help improve building a project for an existing database as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANTS Performance Profiler for the SQL Server Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-21-ants-performance-profiler-for-the-sql-server-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-21-ants-performance-profiler-for-the-sql-server-dev/</guid>
      <description>There are a few .NET tools that until recently I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to work with as much, specifically ANTS Memory Profiler and ANTS Performance Profiler. The memory profiler is more useful for someone focused on memory leaks which a SQL Dev isn&amp;rsquo;t as focused on for performance tuning. However, there are major benefits for diving into SQL Performance tuning with ANTS Performance profiler. I think I&amp;rsquo;d say this tool makes the epic category of my #cooltools kit and will be added to my COOL TOOLS page here for SQL performance tuning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update SSMS With PS1</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-03-update-ssms-with-ps1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-03-update-ssms-with-ps1/</guid>
      <description>Update &amp;ldquo;Updated: 2018-03-29&amp;rdquo; Use Chocolatey. This page keeps changing it&amp;rsquo;s structure, so the regex to parse for Ketarin and this PS1 script keep breaking. Updated to latest version as of 2018-03-29, but recommend checking out the Chocolately Package created for SSMS for this by flcdrg as chocolately is a much nicer way to keep up to date and more likely long-term to succeed than my gist :-) To use chocolatey (after setup), you only have to use choco upgrade sql-server-management-studio which is much easier to remember than using this gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Tool VSCODE called from SQL Management Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-26-edit-in-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-26-edit-in-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Previous Related Post: Split personality text editing in SSMS with Sublime Text 3
In this prior post I wrote about how to call Sublime Text 3 from SSMS to allow improved text manipulation to be quickly called from an active query window in SQL Management Studio. Vscode is a newer editor from Microsoft, and the argument calls took a little work to get working. Here is what I found for having your SQL file open in vscode via call from SSMS (I imagine also works in Visual Studio 2017 this way as well).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add User To Admin Group on Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-07-add-user-to-admin-group-on-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-07-add-user-to-admin-group-on-machine/</guid>
      <description>In setting up some build machines for development, it&amp;rsquo;s tedious to go and add several users to the admin group. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet to expedite that task and help you setup more quickly.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices: Defining Explicit Length for Varchar/Nvarchar</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-07-best-practices-defining-explicit-length-for-varchar-nvarchar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-06-07-best-practices-defining-explicit-length-for-varchar-nvarchar/</guid>
      <description>SA0080 : Do not use VARCHAR or NVARCHAR data types without specifying length. Level: Warning
 When using varchar/nvarchar it should be explicitly defined. This can be a very nasty bug to track down as often nothing will be thrown if not checked in an application. Instead, ensure your script explicitly defines the smallest length that fits your requirements. The reason I rate this as a very dangerous practice, is that no error is thrown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Module Improvements for SQL Server in 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-31-powershell-module-improvements-for-sql-server-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-31-powershell-module-improvements-for-sql-server-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>info &amp;ldquo;Updated: 2018-03-19&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t use these much, if any now. Check out dbatools which is a much better module with a full range of features to save you a ton of time.
 simple setup A major improvement that seems to have quietly slipped into the sql developers world is an improved SQLServer powershell module. The improved module is finally available in the powershell gallery, allowing a super quick setup on a server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running InfluxDB as a service in Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-24-running-influx-db-as-a-service-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-24-running-influx-db-as-a-service-in-windows/</guid>
      <description>Other Posts in Series  Running InfluxDb As A Service in Windows Setting Up InfluxDb, Chronograf, and Grafana for the SqlServer Dev InfluxDB And Annotations Capturing Perfmon Counters With Telegraf  Run as a Service As part of the process to setup some metrics collections for sql-server based on perfmon counters I&amp;rsquo;ve been utilizing InfluxDB. Part of getting started on this is ensuring InfluxDB runs as a service instead of requiring me to launch the exe manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up InfluxDb, Chronograf, and Grafana for the SqlServer Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-17-setting-up-influx-db-chronograf-and-grafana-for-the-sql-server-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-17-setting-up-influx-db-chronograf-and-grafana-for-the-sql-server-dev/</guid>
      <description>Other Posts in Series  Running InfluxDb As A Service in Windows Setting Up InfluxDb, Chronograf, and Grafana for the SqlServer Dev InfluxDB And Annotations Capturing Perfmon Counters With Telegraf  There are some beautiful ways to visualize time series data with the tools I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over. This post is purely focused on the initial setup and saving you some time there. In a future post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how some of these tools can help you visualize your server performance in a powerful way, including taking metrics from multiple types of servers that be working with SQL Server, and combining the metrics when appropriate to give a full picture of performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Windows Updates for Development</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-10-automate-windows-updates-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-10-automate-windows-updates-for-development/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve run into the case where I wanted updates continually applied, while the machine still was part of the GPO that didn&amp;rsquo;t automatically install updates. For this developer and test oriented machine I wanted every update applied.
I utilized a great module for this and created a script to setup the task and logging to make this an easy task.
If you experience an issue with the WindowsUpdate Vs Microsoft update as the configured update provider, then you can just change the switch in the script for -MicrosoftUpdate to -WindowsUpdate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Fonts For The Newb</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-08-programming-fonts-for-the-newb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-05-08-programming-fonts-for-the-newb/</guid>
      <description>the camps Once you get into coding fonts, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that there are two primary camps.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t give a crap about it. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll use defaults for everything and probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t care if I was coding in Arial&amp;rdquo;. If this is you, then this post is definitely not for you. Please continue to enjoy Comic Sans with my pity. :-) Font aficionados &amp;ldquo;Your world will change forever once you use this specific font!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TFS Custom Task - Service Actions (for TFS 2015 Update 2.1 or before)</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-03-07-tfs-custom-task-service-actions-for-tfs-2015-update-2.1-or-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-03-07-tfs-custom-task-service-actions-for-tfs-2015-update-2.1-or-before/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, boolean values for custom VSTS tasks for versions prior to TFS 2015 Update 3) require some special handling as they don&amp;rsquo;t pass the checkbox values as actual powershell $true or $false. Instead the task passes this information along as true or false. To properly handle this you&amp;rsquo;ll need to pass in the value as a string then convert to boolean.
I found a great start on working on this solution in a blog post by Rene which has more detail, so check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Hack: When you need a mouse pad</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-02-24-life-hack-when-you-need-a-mouse-pad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-02-24-life-hack-when-you-need-a-mouse-pad/</guid>
      <description>My Logitech Master mouse went on the fritz&amp;hellip; Requiring me to use my trusty Microsoft mouse. This is an optical based mouse based mouse that started driving me insane with the lack of precision. This exhibited random skips and overall lack of agreeability. I ran across some posts mentioning optical mice have issues with certain surfaces making it hard to detect precise movements and suggested using a surface with a pattern or irregularity, even a piece of paper being scribbled on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Idea Jeans: Query Optimization Through Minification</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-01-23-bad-idea-jeans-query-optimization-through-minification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-01-23-bad-idea-jeans-query-optimization-through-minification/</guid>
      <description>SQL is pretty verbose compared to some languages. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big disappointment that I have to type out select customer from dbo.customers where id = 2 instead of a much simpler syntax like dbo.Customers &#39; Customer like Powershell might offer. As I considered the disappointing verbosity of sql server, I considered that perhaps one way to reduce network traffic, save electricity, and aid the garrulous language known as sql might be to require all code running to be minified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Set Powershell Variables from json</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-05-dynamically-set-powershell-variables-from-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-12-05-dynamically-set-powershell-variables-from-json/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created this small snippet to allow a list of values from a json file be turned into variables to work with. For working with a fixed list of configuration values, this might be helpful to reduce some coding effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell ISE: Updating Theme</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-09-powershell-ise-updating-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-09-powershell-ise-updating-theme/</guid>
      <description>For all the dark theme aficionados, or those who just want a better theme than the default, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick set of directions to update your ISE.1. Go to download a theme from Github &amp;gt; PowerShell_ISE_Themes 2. Unzip 3. Go to ISE &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Colors &amp;amp; Fonts &amp;gt; Manage Themes 4. Import selected theme 5. For consistency, adjust the background and forecolor of the console pane as well as the text background to match if you want to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Search Only Results from the last year</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-04-27-google-search-only-results-from-the-last-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-04-27-google-search-only-results-from-the-last-year/</guid>
      <description>Tech changes quick. Reading google postings from something in 2009 is not my first choice.I found an option after digging through some google discussion posts on how to setup the default search in chrome (also applies to other browsers) to automatically apply the advanced filter option for &amp;ldquo;results in last year&amp;rdquo;.
 Go to chrome settings menu  Navigate to manage search engines  Enter the new search engine option .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>