<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redgate on sheldonhull.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/redgate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Redgate on sheldonhull.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/redgate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ANTS Performance Profiler for the SQL Server Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-21-ants-performance-profiler-for-the-sql-server-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-07-21-ants-performance-profiler-for-the-sql-server-dev/</guid>
      <description>There are a few .NET tools that until recently I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to work with as much, specifically ANTS Memory Profiler and ANTS Performance Profiler. The memory profiler is more useful for someone focused on memory leaks which a SQL Dev isn&amp;rsquo;t as focused on for performance tuning. However, there are major benefits for diving into SQL Performance tuning with ANTS Performance profiler. I think I&amp;rsquo;d say this tool makes the epic category of my #cooltools kit and will be added to my COOL TOOLS page here for SQL performance tuning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gate SQL Clone (#1) - Initial Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/red-gate-sql-clone-1-initial-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/red-gate-sql-clone-1-initial-setup/</guid>
      <description>Note this was during earlier beta usage, so some of the UI and other features will have been updated more. I plan on writing more on this promising tool as I get a chance to dive into it more, especially the powershell cmdlets for database cloning automation. In the meantime, I believe the permissions issue is still relevant, so I&amp;rsquo;ll post this as a reminder in case someone is working through the initial setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Compare on Temporal Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-28-data-compare-on-temporal-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-28-data-compare-on-temporal-tables/</guid>
      <description>I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen much talk on doing data comparisons on temporal tables, as they are a new feature. I went through the exercise to compare current to historical to see how Red Gate &amp;amp; Devart handled this. I&amp;rsquo;m a part of the Friends of Red Gate program, so love checking out their latest updates, and I&amp;rsquo;m also a regular tester on Devart which also provides fantastic tools. Both handled Temporal Tables with aplomb, so here&amp;rsquo;s a quick walk through on how I did this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating Database Collation - The Red Gate Way</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-10-migrating-database-collation-the-red-gate-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-10-10-migrating-database-collation-the-red-gate-way/</guid>
      <description>I had some cross database comparisons that I wanted to simplify, but ensuring the collation matched. The amount of objects that I would have had to drop and recreate was a bit daunting, so I looked for a way to migrate the database to a different collation.Using the Red Gate toolkit, I was able to achieve this pretty quickly. There are other methods with copying data built in to SSMS that could do some of these steps, but the seamless approach was really nice with the SQL Toolbelt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSMS - Connection Color with SQL Prompt &amp; SSMSBoost</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-23-ssms-connection-color-with-sql-prompt-ssms-boost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-23-ssms-connection-color-with-sql-prompt-ssms-boost/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t explored the visual color coding of tabs based on pattern matches with SQL Prompt, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest you check this out. Earlier iterations of Red Gate&amp;rsquo;s SQL Prompt did not change tab color immediately when the connection was changed. Red Gate&amp;rsquo;s tab color could get out of sync occasionally, so I stopped depending on it.
Apparently this has been improved on and my testing now shows that the tab recoloring for connections is changing when the connection is updated immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install ReadyRoll via Command Line</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-18-install-ready-roll-via-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2016-08-18-install-ready-roll-via-command-line/</guid>
      <description>command line install options ReadyRoll has some great features, including the ability to use without cost on a build server. If you want to ease setup on multiple build servers you could create a simple command line install step against the EXE.
future changes ReadyRoll was recently acquired by Redgate, so the installer options may change in the future to be more inline with the standard Redgate installer. For now, this is a way to automate an install/updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Gate SQL Source Control v4 offers schema locks</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2015-08-12-red-gate-sql-source-control-v4-offers-schema-locks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2015-08-12-red-gate-sql-source-control-v4-offers-schema-locks/</guid>
      <description>Red Gate Documentation Update Looks like the rapid release channel now has a great feature for locking database objects that you are working on. Having worked in a shared environment before, this could have been a major help. It&amp;rsquo;s like the poor man&amp;rsquo;s version of checking an object out in visual studio except on database objects! With multiple developers working in a shared environment, this might help reduce conflicting multiple changes on the same object.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>