<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on sheldonhull.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on sheldonhull.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sheldonhull.com/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time With Family - Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-12-31-time-with-family-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-12-31-time-with-family-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my personal quest as a creative who has a passion for videography to try and capture simple moments during my life with family. There are plenty of epic indie films, and I can&amp;rsquo;t commit this type of time with a day job, family, and other interests. I think this is a good start. Thanks to Robert &amp;amp; Steph for their hospitality and making this a special thanksgiving. Was a wonderful time with family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delight in the Little Moments</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-11-10-delight-in-the-little-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-11-10-delight-in-the-little-moments/</guid>
      <description>This last Easter I had some fun with the kids at their grandparents. Remember the days of spinning until you were nauseous? Was fun to watch the kids enjoying this so I took a few clips, nothing fancy, just a snapshot of enjoying the little moments in life.
Thinking I&amp;rsquo;ll try this approach for a while. Small 2 minute videos that aren&amp;rsquo;t refined a lot are easy for me to produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the World Little Ella</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-08-welcome-to-the-world-little-ella/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-09-08-welcome-to-the-world-little-ella/</guid>
      <description>Proud to announce Ella the newest addition to my family joined us today @ 6:19pm, weighing in at 6lbs and 11 ounces. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s 6lbs of cuteness. :-) I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly blessed to have this third addition to my family, and look forward to treasuring every moment with her. God sure knows how to give an amazing gift!
It was a rough 24 hours resulting in our first cesarean experience. This was a bit intense, but Sarah pulled through as a trooper, and we are now finished with post-operation recovery, and enjoying time with our new bundle of awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Waterlogged Texan Reporting In from Northpoint Tomball</title>
      <link>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-waterlogged-texan-reporting-in-from-northpoint-tomball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sheldonhull.com/blog/2017-08-29-a-waterlogged-texan-reporting-in-from-northpoint-tomball/</guid>
      <description>Waterlogged What a crazy weekend. Choose to evacuate the family as water was slowly creeping up closer to the house. I was ready today when I made it back to the house to see the water in the house, but to my astonishment it was only half-way up the driveway. Turning down the road 1 house away, many houses did not fare so well, and water looks to have made it in many homes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>